Fernando Gaona Juarez

FullStack Developer Mexico City, Mexico (GMT-5) (+52) 2223420854 iti.carlosfernandogaonajuarez@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/fernandogaona23/

Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience in software development using Java (Spring boot, Maven,Linux, Bash Scripting,Java framework (TOMCAT/ JIBX/LOG4J/ GWT,GIT and ci/cd pipelines), NodeJS in the backend, and JavaScript (Angular Material, VueJs) and with 2 +years of experience in software development using Ruby (Ruby on Rails), in the frontend. I also have experience using AWS and Swagger in Cloud and Mysql, Oracle DB, and Postgresql as databases. I'm looking for a position in a multicultural team that allows me to keep growing and learning in my tech career journey.

EXPERIENCE

ZentaGroup Software Development Engineer — September 2023 - Today

- Increase by 10% productivity by developing a system manager for a resiter company.
- Reduced 15% of bugs found in the system transaction for Transbak company.
- Provided comprehensive Unix and SQL production support for Transbank Company, a leading provider of register systems.

Tech Stack: Java, Spring Boot,Linux,Bash Scripting, PostgreSQL, snowflake, SQL,Unix queries, Kafka, Elastic, grafana, Kubernetes, Docker, cloud-native application development,GIT and ci/cd pipelines

QAD Software Development Engineer — November 2022 - September 2023

- Increase by 15% sales by developing a management platform for the Looker client.
- Reduced 35% of bugs found in the looker system by fixing the microservices-based in Kafka
- Provided comprehensive Unix and SQL production support for QAD Company, a leading provider of register systems.
- **Tech Stack**:Java17,Scala, Springboot,ReactJS,GraphQL, Kafka,,Linux,Bash Scripting, OpenShift, CI/CD, Google Cloud,AWS, Junit, MongoDB,Docker, Kubernetes,UNIX, Api's,GIT and ci/cd pipelines.

Softtek, Software Development Engineer — July 2021 - November 2022

- Increase by 35% delivery of packages in NorthAmerica And Europe by developing a tracking number system as a Software Engineer for the UPS.
- Reduced 45% of errors and bugs found in the tracking number system by fixing the dependencies of the pom.xml. of spring-boot(java).
- Participated in the migration of containers of Kubernetes to Openshift.

Tech Stack: Java17, Springboot, Kafka,Scala,NodeJs,ExpressJS,ReactsJs,AWS,Postgresql,MongoDB,Linux,Bash Scripting,OpenShift, Google Cloud, Azure, Junit, Docker, Kubernetes, Api's,GIT and ci/cd pipelines

AppsPool, Ruby on Rails Developer — May 2020 - July 2021

- Increased by 25% sales by developing a management platform that consists of a point of sales for local companies using Ruby On Rails and Gem devices for the administrative module in the back-end, ReactJs in the front-end and Postgresql as a database.
- Developed a blog application to share news for the firm E-consulta using Ruby On Rails and Sqlite3. This project consists of 4 modules: Login, Register, News Upload, and Notes.
- The final achievement of those 2 projects was the launch of the website and administrative platform developed in Ruby allowing users to upload information from approximately 10k registers monthly.
 - **Tech Stack:** Ruby, Ruby on Rails,ReactJs,Linux,Bash Scripting, AWS, Postgresql, Rspec, Docker, Kubernetes,NodeJs,ExpressJS, TDD,

Api's.

Estrella Roja, Java(SpringBoot) Developer — January 2020 - April 2020

- Developed the rafle web application using Java(SpringBoot), Angular, and Postgresql This application has 5 main modules: login, register, upload files, create rafle, and lookup of winners.
- Improved design of 50% patterns by implementing SCRUM methodology and MVC (Model View Controller) and repositories. The mobile application is currently in the play store and app store and has 100k+ downloads. **Tech Stack**: Java, Springboot, AWS, MYSql, Junit, Solid, Docker, Kubernetes, TDD, Api's, Nodels, Express|S, WebSocket, Linux, Bash Scripting.

C&F,Teach Leader and Java Trainer(ToksMx)— November 2015 - January 2020

- Enhanced by 45% user experience by leading a team of 15 persons (from financial engineers to software developers) in the development and implementation of the Savings bank for many Mexican companies, including Toks. Also, this implementation allowed the customers to track money around the world in real-time
- Managed the workflow and assignments for the team members, according to everyone's skills in order to boost productivity.
- Responsibilities as Java and Ruby Trainer are to teach data structures with Java and Ruby and also teach oop also Design Java training programs, I worked with software engineers in the Java infrastructure team.
- Responsibilities as software developer are writing code with the best practices, applied the best data structure in the code, and applied solid principles

Tech Stack: Java. Spring Boot, RabbitMQ, REST, SOAP,Linux,Bash Scripting,AWS, Postgresql, Rspec, Docker, Kubernetes, TDD, Apis.

PROJECTS

AppsPool - https://github.com/Fernando21GJ/app-administrativa-rails-master - 2020

• Implemented and developed an administration software that has its main function in the department store, mall, and little stores. It is composed of 11 main modules and is small in source code. The software is a free solution for companies that need it.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Advanced: Java, JavaScript, TypeScript; Intermediate: PHP, Python, C#; Basic: Go, Scala, Swift.

Frameworks Tools: Advanced: Spring Boot, Angular; Intermediate: ExpressJs, ReactJS, Ionic; Basic: VueJs, Elixir, ADF.

Data Base: Advanced: Postgresql, Mysql, MongoDB; Intermediate: OracleDB, SQL Server, Redis; Basic: Sqlite3, DynamoDB. **Tools: Aws, Azure Devops, Jira, GitHub, Gitlab, Git, Bitbucket, DevOps.**

Agile: Scrum ,Agile, Kanban.

Languages: Fluent: English; Native: Spanish.

EDUCATION

Universidad Politécnica de Tlaxcala - Tlaxcala, Tlaxcala. Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology Engineer. July 2019.

CERTIFICATIONS

Data Structures + Algorithms – Zero To Master Academy. 2022.